<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting started on ThingsDB documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getting started on ThingsDB documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Build from source</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/build-from-source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/build-from-source/</guid>
      <description>Install the following dependencies:
 libuv1 libpcre2 libyajl libcleri (&amp;gt;=0.12.1)  When using Debian/Ubuntu; libuv1, libpcre2 and libyajl can be installed using apt:
sudo apt-get install -y \  libuv1-dev \  libpcre2-dev \  libyajl-dev At least version 0.12.1 for library libcleri-dev is required.
git clone https://github.com/transceptor-technology/libcleri.git cd libcleri/Release make sudo make install Next, clone the project
git clone https://github.com/thingsdb/ThingsDB.git cd ThingsDB/Release make clean &amp;amp;&amp;amp; make You might want to create a symlink like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuration</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/configuration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/configuration/</guid>
      <description>ThingsDB can start with a configuration file and/or with environment variables. However be aware that the environment variables will overwrite the configuration file settings if both apply to the same setting.
   Variable Default Description     THINGSDB_BIND_CLIENT_ADDR 0.0.0.0 Bind client connections to this address. This may also be an IPv6 address like ::.   THINGSDB_BIND_NODE_ADDR 0.0.0.0 Bind node connections to this address. This may also be an IPv6 address like ::.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Start up node</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/start-up-node/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/start-up-node/</guid>
      <description>ThingsDB can work with a single node but is designed to work with at least two nodes but three nodes are preferred. Running on three nodes brings redundancy and ensures the database stays operational, even while you for example upgrade ThingsDB to a newer version.
 After building the source code and making a symlink, you can start your first node using the following command. You need to add the --init flag to initialize a new ThingsDB store.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Readiness and liveness</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/readiness-liveness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/getting-started/readiness-liveness/</guid>
      <description>When http_status_port is set in the configuration file or the environment variable THINGSDB_HTTP_STATUS_PORT then /status, /ready and /healthy are available. These can be used for readiness and liveness requests.
Liveness The ThingsDB /healthy check will respond with a 200 OK whenever possible and will never respond with an error. So only if no response is received in some reasonable amount of time, the node should be considered as unhealthy. It is common to use the /healthy check as liveness probe in environments like Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>