<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Socket on ThingsDB documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Socket on ThingsDB documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Example ping</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/ping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/ping/</guid>
      <description>Can be used as keep-alive. A successful ping will respond with a PONG (16)
No authorization is required for sending a ping request.
 Example A Ping package has no data so we only need to construct the header:
 Data length (0) \x00\x00\x00\x00 Identifier (0) \x00\x00 Ping package type (32) \x20 Inverse type check bit (223) \xdf   Sending the Ping package
 \x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x00\x20\xdf   Responding Pong package</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example auth</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/auth/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/auth/</guid>
      <description>Used for authorizing the socket connection. A successful authentication will respond with OK (17)
Authorization can be done by using either a username and password combination or by a token.
 Syntax username/password
 [username, password]   Syntax token
 &amp;quot;token_string&amp;quot;  Example username/password As an example we create an authentication package for the default admin user with password pass.
This is the package data for our authentication request:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example query</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/query/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/query/</guid>
      <description>Query ThingsDB. A successful query request will respond with a DATA (18) package.
 Syntax
 [scope, code, {vars}]  The vars in the query are optional and may be omitted. When used, vars must be a map where the keys represent the variable names and the values the values for the variable.
The socket needs to be authorized before for sending a query request. See the auth example for how to authorize a socket connection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example run</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/run/</guid>
      <description>Run a procedure in ThingsDB. A successful run request will respond with a DATA (18) package.
 Syntax
 [scope, procedure, ...args]  The args are parsed (and must match) to the procedure.
The socket needs to be authorized before for sending a run request. See the auth example for how to authorize a socket connection.
 Example As an example we assume there is a procedure created in the @thingsdb scope, called &amp;ldquo;add_one&amp;rdquo; which just adds one to a given value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example watch</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/watch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/watch/</guid>
      <description>Subscript for watching a node or things in ThingsDB. A successful run request will respond with a OK (17) package.
 Syntax
 [scope, ...IDs]  The IDs are the thing ID&amp;rsquo;s you want to watch.
The socket needs to be authorized before for sending a watch request. See the auth example for how to authorize a socket connection.
 Example As an example we assume that we want to watch a thing with ID 3 for changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example error response</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/error-response/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/socket/error-response/</guid>
      <description>In this example we perform a query request and assume the socket connection is not authenticated yet. We then look at the error response.
Example As an example we will perform a useless query with as code just the simple equation 1 + 1; and we will use the @thingsdb scope to perform the query on.
This is the data we want to pack:
[&amp;quot;@t&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;1 + 1;&amp;quot;]
Serializing the above using MessagePack results in the following 11 bytes:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>