<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Node API on ThingsDB documentation</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/</link><description>Recent content in Node API on ThingsDB documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>backup_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/backup_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/backup_info/</guid><description>Returns information about a specific scheduled backup.
Value Description created_at Time Stamp when the backup schedule is created. file_template Backup file template. files List of successful backup files. id Backup Id. max_files Maximum number of backup files to store. The oldest file will be removed once max_files is reached. next_run Only available when the backup job is scheduled to run.</description></item><item><title>backups_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/backups_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/backups_info/</guid><description>Returns backup schedule information about all backup schedules in the selected node scope.
See the backup_info() function documentation for an example of the exposed backup schedule information.
This function does not generate a change.
Function backups_info()
Arguments None
Return value List with backup schedule mpdata about all backup schedules in the selected node scope.</description></item><item><title>backups_ok</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/backups_ok/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/backups_ok/</guid><description>Returns false if at least one backup had failed (result code != 0). In all other cases this function returns true (also when no backups are available or not yet started).
This function does not generate a change.
Function backups_ok()
Arguments None
Return value Returns false if at least one backup has failed, otherwise this function returns true.</description></item><item><title>counters</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/counters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/counters/</guid><description>Returns counters for the ThingsDB node in the selected scope. Counters start all at zero when ThingsDB is started, or when the counters are reset by using reset_counters()'.
Counters give information about things, queries and changes. If you suspect failed queries, then the counters might provide you with more information.
Counter Description average_change_duration The average change duration in seconds. Change duration is measured from the time a change is created (before the final Id is assigned), until the actual change is committed to ThingsDB.</description></item><item><title>del_backup</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/del_backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/del_backup/</guid><description>Delete a scheduled backup. If the scheduled backup was pending, the backup job will be cancelled.
This function does not generate a change.
Function del_backup(Id, [delete_files])
Arguments Argument Type Description Id int Backup Id to delete. delete_files bool (optional) Delete related backup files from disk (or Google Cloud Storage). Default is false. Return value Returns nil.</description></item><item><title>has_backup</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/has_backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/has_backup/</guid><description>Determines if a backup exists in ThingsDB.
This function does not generate a change.
Function has_backup(Id)
Arguments Argument Type Description Id int (required) Backup Id to check. Return value Returns true if a backup with a given Id exists and otherwise false.
Example This code shows an example use case of has_backup():
has_backup(123); Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>new_backup</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/new_backup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/new_backup/</guid><description>Schedule a new backup.
Backups are created using tar and gzip. Once a backup is made, the .tar.gz backup file can be used to recover ThingsDB, or can be used to load the ThingsDB into another node. The result value is a backup Id. This Id can be used by backup_info(..) for details about the backup schedule job, or can be used to delete the backup schedule.
If Google Cloud Storage is configured then it is possible to create backups directly into Google Cloud Storage.</description></item><item><title>node_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/node_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/node_info/</guid><description>Returns information about the node in the selected scope. See scopes for more information on how to target a specific node scope.
Like all other info(..) functions, this function returns mpdata which can be loaded to extract one or more properties. See example 2.
Value Description architecture Machine architecture of this node, for example amd64. archive_files Number of archive files. May decrease after a full store during away mode.</description></item><item><title>nodes_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/nodes_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/nodes_info/</guid><description>Returns information about all ThingsDB nodes.
Value Description node_name A node will publish itself to other nodes using the node name. This can be for example an IP address, hostname , or a fully qualified domain name (FQDN) of the node. committed_change_id Last known committed change Id on the node. node_id Id which is assigned to the node. port TCP port on which the node is listening for node connections.</description></item><item><title>reset_counters</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/reset_counters/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/reset_counters/</guid><description>Resets the counters for the ThingsDB node you are connected too. Other nodes are not affected. This will set the started_at counter value to the current UNIX time-stamp in seconds and all other counters to 0 (zero).
This function does not generate a change.
Function reset_counters()
Arguments None
Return value Returns nil.
Example This code will reset the counters on a node:
// resets counters on the node in this scope reset_counters(); Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>restart_module</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/restart_module/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/restart_module/</guid><description>Restarts a given module on the select node scope.
If you want to restart the module on all nodes, you can use the deploy_module(name, nil) function with nil as second argument.
This function does not generate a change.
Function restart_module(name)
Arguments Argument Type Description name str (required) Module to restart. Return value Returns nil.
Example This code will reset the counters on a node:</description></item><item><title>set_log_level</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/set_log_level/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/set_log_level/</guid><description>Change the log level for the node in the selected scope.
ThingsDB will then log all levels greater than or equal to the specified level. For example, a default log_level of warning will log warning, error and critical messages.
This function does not generate a change.
Log Levels Name Int Description DEBUG 0 Display debug messages (can result in large amount of logging). INFO 1 Informational messages.</description></item><item><title>shutdown</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/shutdown/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/node-api/shutdown/</guid><description>Shutdown the node in the selected scope. This is a clean shutdown, allowing all other nodes (and clients) to disconnect.
At least CHANGE privileges on the @node scope are required to shutdown a node.
This function does not generate a change.
Function shutdown()
Arguments None.
Return value Returns nil.</description></item></channel></rss>