<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Connect on ThingsDB documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Connect on ThingsDB documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Authentication</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/authentication/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/authentication/</guid>
      <description>ThingsDB supports authentication by using a user and password combination, or with a token. A default user admin with password pass is created on a fresh installation. If you did not yet change the default password, you might want to jump to set password.
It might be a good idea to create a new user with minimal privileges and add a new token for this user. See the grant and revoke functions for managing privileges for a user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP API</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/http-api/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/http-api/</guid>
      <description>Before using the HTTP API, make sure at least one node has the API port enabled. By default the API port is enabled and listening to TCP port 9210 but can be disabled or changed with the http_api_port in the configuration file or with the THINGSDB_HTTP_API_PORT environment variable.
The API has support for both MessagePack and JSON and can be used to perform queries and run procedures.
Use MessagePack if possible since this is the data serialization protocol which is used by ThingsDB internally and will therefore be a faster than JSON.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/python/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/python/</guid>
      <description>Use pip to install the python client:
 pip install python-thingsdb  The Python client supports both queries, watching and a framework for using ThingsDB in a really simple way.
 To authorize in Python, use this code:
 import asyncio from thingsdb.client import Client client = Client() loop = asyncio.get_event_loop() async def example(): # replace `localhost` with your ThingsDB server address await client.connect(&#39;localhost&#39;) # replace `amdin` with yout username and `pass` with your password await client.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/connect/go/</guid>
      <description>Explain the Go client&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>