<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Collection API on ThingsDB documentation</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/</link><description>Recent content in Collection API on ThingsDB documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>alt_raise</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/alt_raise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/alt_raise/</guid><description>This function will try a statement. If the statement is successful it will just return the result but in case of an error, it will re-raise the error using a given error code. The following code below will illustrate how alt_raise works:
Without an optional error message
// the following code: res = alt_raise(statement, error_code); // is equivalent to: res = try(statement); if (is_err(res)) { raise(error_code, res.msg()); }; With an error message</description></item><item><title>assert</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/assert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/assert/</guid><description>Raises an assert_err() if the specified expression evaluates to false.
This function does not generate a change.
Function assert(expression [, error_msg])
Arguments Argument Type Description expression any (required) The expression to evaluate. error_msg str (optional) Custom error message. Return value Returns nil if the type of the expression evaluates to true. Otherwise an assert_err() is raised.
In versions before v0.</description></item><item><title>base64_decode</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/base64_decode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/base64_decode/</guid><description>Decode a Base64 encoded string.
See base64_encode for Base64 encoding.
This function does not generate a change.
Function base64_decode(encoded)
Arguments Argument Type Description encoded str/bytes The string value to decode. Return value Decoded bytes value is returned.
Example This code shows an example for base64_decode:
encoded = 'YmFzZTY0IGVuY29kZWQgc3RyaW5n'; // decode data = base64_decode(encoded); // result is of type bytes assert(type(data) == 'bytes'); // return as string str(data); Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>base64_encode</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/base64_encode/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/base64_encode/</guid><description>Encode a str or bytes value using Base64.
See base64_decode for Base64 decoding.
This function does not generate a change.
Function base64_encode(string)
Arguments Argument Type Description string str/bytes The value to encode. Return value Encoded str value is returned.
Example This code shows an example for base64_encode:
encoded = base64_encode('base64 encoded string'); // result is of type str assert(type(encoded) == 'str'); // return encoded; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>bool</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/bool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/bool/</guid><description>Returns a bool from a specified value. If no value is given, false is returned.
Types with a length evaluate to true when the length is not 0, and false otherwise.
This function does not generate a change.
Function bool(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (optional) The value to convert to a boolean value. Return value A boolean value.</description></item><item><title>bytes</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/bytes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/bytes/</guid><description>Convert a value to a byte sequence. If no value is given, an empty byte sequence is returned.
This function does not generate a change.
Function bytes(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (optional) The value where to create a bytes value for.</description></item><item><title>change_id</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/change_id/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/change_id/</guid><description>Returns the current change Id for the running query. The return value will be nil if the query does not require a change.
This function does not generate a change.
Function change_id()
Arguments None
Return value The current change Id or nil when the query does not require a change.
Example Example using change_id():
change_id(); // nil, since no change is required Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>closure</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/closure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/closure/</guid><description>Returns an closure from a given string. If no value is given, the default closure || nil is returned.
This function does not generate a change.
Function closure(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value str (optional) Convert a string into a closure. If omitted the default closure || nil is returned. Return value An new closure.
Example This code shows some return values for closure():</description></item><item><title>datetime</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/datetime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/datetime/</guid><description>Returns a datetime depending on some optional values.
This function does not generate a change.
Function Interface Arguments Description datetime() None Return a datetime with the current date/tine. datetime(ts) int/float Return a datetime from a given UNIX time stamp. datetime(str, [fmt]) str Return a datetime from a given string. See initialize from string for a details. datetime(int, int, int, [int, [int, [int]]], [zone]) int, int,&amp;hellip; str Return a datetime using values for individual time units, with optional time zone.</description></item><item><title>deep</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/deep/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/deep/</guid><description>Set or return the current deep value for the running query. The deep value indicates how far down the result of a query is returned. For example, thing1 may contain a thing2 that contains a thing3. A deep value of 1 would only show the content of thing1 and a deep value of 3 will go as deep as the content of thing3. ThingsDB allows deep to have a value between 0 and 127.</description></item><item><title>del_enum</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/del_enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/del_enum/</guid><description>Deletes an existing enumerator type.
It is not possible to delete a enumerator type which is used by a Type or if one of the enumerator members is still being used. See example below.
This function generates a change.
Function del_enum(enum)
Arguments Argument Type Description enum string Name of the enumerator type to be deleted. Return value The value nil.</description></item><item><title>del_type</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/del_type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/del_type/</guid><description>Deletes an existing Type.
It is not possible to delete a Type which is used by another Type. You should first change or delete the other Type before you are able to delete this Type. See the example below.
If there are still things of the Type you delete, then all things will be converted to non-typed things. No properties will be removed in this process. With type_count(..) you can view the number of things of a certain Type.</description></item><item><title>enum</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enum/</guid><description>Returns a enum member from a given value. A lookup_err() is raised if either the enum or value is not found.
This function does not generate a change.
Function enum(enum, [value])
Arguments Argument Type Description enum str (required) The name of the enumeration type. value any (optional) The value to search the enum member for. If omitted, the default member is returned.</description></item><item><title>enum_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enum_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enum_info/</guid><description>Returns information about a given enumeration type.
Value Description enum_id Internal enum Id (can be used to identify Enums in collection events). created_at Time Stamp when the enum is created. default Default member of this enumerator. The default member is used when implicitly creating a value of this enumerator type. See mod_enum(..) to change the deafult member. modified_at Time Stamp when the enum is last modified or nil if never modified.</description></item><item><title>enum_map</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enum_map/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enum_map/</guid><description>Returns a thing with key/value pairs for all the members of a given enum.
This function does not generate a change.
Function enum_map(enum)
Arguments Argument Type Description enum str The name of the enum to return as a thing. Return value Returns a thing with key/value pairs for all the members of the given enumerator.
Example This code shows the output of enum_map():</description></item><item><title>enums_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enums_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/enums_info/</guid><description>Returns enumeration type information about all the enum&amp;rsquo;s within a collection scope.
See the enum_info() function documentation for an example of the exposed information.
This function does not generate a change.
Function enums_info()
Arguments None
Return value List with mpdata about all enumeration types in the collection scope.</description></item><item><title>err</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/err/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/err/</guid><description>Returns an error.
This function does not generate a change.
Function err([code, [message]])
Arguments Argument Type Description code int (optional) Integer error code between -127 and -50, defaults to -100. See error documentation for build-in errors. message str (optional) Optional error message. Return value An error value (in a client response, an error value will be packed as a string value with the error message).</description></item><item><title>float</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/float/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/float/</guid><description>Returns a float from a specified value. If no value is given, the default float 0.0 is returned.
If the specified value is of type str, then the initial characters of the string are converted until a non-digit character is found. Initial white space is ignored and the number may start with an optional + or - sign.
Type bool values are converted to 1.0 for true and 0.0 for false.</description></item><item><title>future</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/future/</guid><description>Returns a future. It is not possible to assign a future to a collection or add the future to a list. If you do, then nil will be assigned instead.
If you want to use the return value from a future, you need to use then(..) and errors might be captured using the else(..) function.
A future&amp;rsquo;s callback will get its own change-Id in case one is required. This means that it is possible to use a future to prevent a change in a query on some conditions (see last example).</description></item><item><title>has_enum</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/has_enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/has_enum/</guid><description>Determines if a enumerator type exists in the current @collection scope.
This function does not generate a change.
Function has_enum(enum)
Arguments Argument Type Description enum str (required) Enum name to check. Return value Returns true if a enumerator type with a given name exists and otherwise false.
Example This code shows an example use case of has_enum():
has_enum('XXX'); Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>has_type</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/has_type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/has_type/</guid><description>Determines if a Type exists in the current @collection scope.
This function does not generate a change.
Function has_type(type)
Arguments Argument Type Description type str (required) Type name to check. Return value Returns true if a Type with a given name exists and otherwise false.
Example This code shows an example use case of has_type():
has_type('XXX'); Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>int</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/int/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/int/</guid><description>Returns an int from a specified value. If no value is given, the default integer 0 is returned.
If the specified value was a float value, then the new integer value will be rounded towards zero.
If the specified value is of type str, then the initial characters of the string are converted until a non-digit character is found. Initial white space is ignored and the number may start with an optional + or - sign.</description></item><item><title>is_array</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_array/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_array/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type list or tuple or not. The functions is_list and is_tuple can be used to check if the array is mutable.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_array(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the value passed is an array, else it returns false.</description></item><item><title>is_ascii</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_ascii/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_ascii/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type str and contains only valid ascii characters.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_ascii(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type str and contains only ascii characters, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_ascii():</description></item><item><title>is_bool</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_bool/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_bool/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a bool or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_bool(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a boolean, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_bool():
[ is_bool( true ), is_bool( 'true' ), is_bool( nil ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_bytes</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_bytes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_bytes/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type bytes or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_bytes(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type bytes, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_bytes():</description></item><item><title>is_closure</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_closure/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_closure/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a closure or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_closure(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a closure, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_closure():
[ is_closure( || nil ), is_closure( nil ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_datetime</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_datetime/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_datetime/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type datetime.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_datetime(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type timeval, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_utf8():
[ is_datetime( timeval(2013, 2, 6) ), is_datetime( datetime(2013, 2, 6) ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_enum</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_enum/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is an enumeration type member or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_enum(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type enum, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_enum():</description></item><item><title>is_err</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_err/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_err/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a error or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_err(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is an error, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_err():
[ is_err( err() ), is_err( zero_div_err() ), is_err( try((1 / 0)) ), is_err( try((1 / 1)) ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_float</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_float/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_float/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a floating point value or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_float(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a float, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_float():</description></item><item><title>is_future</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_future/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a future value or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_future(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a future, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_float():
[ is_future( future(nil) ), is_future( future(nil).</description></item><item><title>is_inf</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_inf/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_inf/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a positive or negative infinity.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_inf(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a positive or negative infinity, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_inf():</description></item><item><title>is_int</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_int/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_int/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is an integer or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_int(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is an integer, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_int():
[ is_int( 42 ), is_int( 0x2a ), is_int( 42.</description></item><item><title>is_list</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_list/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a list or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_list(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a list, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_list():
[ is_list( [] ), is_list( tmp = [['nested']] ), is_list( tmp[0] ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_mpdata</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_mpdata/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_mpdata/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type mpdata or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_mpdata(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type mpdata, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_mpdata():</description></item><item><title>is_nan</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_nan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_nan/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a number.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_nan(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is not a number, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_nan():
[ is_nan( true ), is_nan( 123 ), is_nan( 3.</description></item><item><title>is_nil</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_nil/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_nil/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is nil.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_nil(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is nil, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_nil():
[ is_nil( nil ), is_nil( 0 ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_raw</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_raw/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_raw/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type str or bytes.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_raw(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type str or bytes, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_raw():</description></item><item><title>is_regex</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_regex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_regex/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type regex or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_regex(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type regex, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_regex():</description></item><item><title>is_room</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_room/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a room or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_room(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a room, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_room():
[ is_room( thing() ), is_room( room() ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_set</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_set/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_set/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a set or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_set(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a set, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_set():
[ is_set( [] ), is_set( set() ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_str</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_str/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_str/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type str.
The value is not explicitly checked for valid UTF-8 characters, use is_utf8() if you want to check for valid UTF-8 data.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_str(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type str, else false.</description></item><item><title>is_task</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_task/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_task/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a task or not.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_task(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a task, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_task():
[ is_task( thing() ), is_task( task(datetime(), ||nil) ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_thing</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_thing/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a thing or not.
Typed things are also things, so this function returns true for both typed and non-typed things.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_thing(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a thing, else it returns false.</description></item><item><title>is_time_zone</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_time_zone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_time_zone/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type str and contains a valid time zone (see time_zones_info() for a list with all available time zones).
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_time_zone(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type str and contains a valid time zone, else false.</description></item><item><title>is_timeval</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_timeval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_timeval/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type timeval.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_timeval(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type timeval, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_utf8():
[ is_timeval( timeval(2013, 2, 6) ), is_timeval( datetime(2013, 2, 6) ), ]; Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>is_tuple</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_tuple/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_tuple/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is a tuple or not. At least nested arrays are of kind tuple.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_tuple(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is a tuple, else it returns false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_tuple():</description></item><item><title>is_utf8</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_utf8/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/is_utf8/</guid><description>This function determines whether the provided value is of type str and contains valid UTF-8 characters.
This function does not generate a change.
Function is_utf8(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to be tested. Return value Returns true if the given value is of type raw and contains valid utf8, else false.
Example This code shows some return values for is_utf8():</description></item><item><title>json_dump</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/json_dump/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/json_dump/</guid><description>Converts a ThingsDB value in to a JSON string.
This function does not generate a change.
Function json_dump(value, [options])
Arguments Argument Type Description value any The value to convert into a JSON string. options thing Thing with options. Options Option Type Description deep int Specify how deep the value must be converted.</description></item><item><title>json_load</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/json_load/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/json_load/</guid><description>Converts a JSON string into a ThingsDB value.
This function does not generate a change.
Function json_load(string)
Arguments Argument Type Description string str JSON string to convert. Return value ThingsDB value.
Example This code shows an example for json_load:
json_load('{&amp;quot;success&amp;quot;: true}'); Return value in JSON format
{ &amp;#34;success&amp;#34;: true }</description></item><item><title>list</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/list/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/list/</guid><description>Returns a new empty list or returns a list for a given set.
This function does not generate a change.
Function list([value])
Arguments Argument Type Description value set/list/tuple (optional) Optional value to initialize the list. If the argument is already a list or tuple, the return value will be the same list or tuple. Return value A new list (Unless the given argument was a tuple or list, then no conversion takes place and the given list or tuple will be the return value).</description></item><item><title>log</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/log/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/log/</guid><description>Might be used for debugging code. The message will be logged as a warning message on the console of the node which is processing the request. When you are connected using a socket stream, then a warning message with code 2 will be send to the client as well.
This function does not generate a change.
Function log(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value str/any (required) Value to log.</description></item><item><title>new</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/new/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/new/</guid><description>Creates a new typed thing of a defined Type.
When possible it is preferred to use the syntax MyType{...} to create a thing of a certain Type. However, sometimes you need to create an thing dynamically with the Type&amp;rsquo;s name as variable and then new() can be used.
Since version v0.9.2 the value argument is no longer required. If not given all properties will be set to their default values.</description></item><item><title>new_type</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/new_type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/new_type/</guid><description>Creates a new Type. This function only creates a new type and does not allow you to specify any fields. With the set_type() function you can define the fields for the new type.
It is possible to use set_type directly without calling new_type first. However, sometimes you want to cross reference two types so you want both type to exists before calling set_type.
This function generates a change.
Function new_type(type, [wrap_only, [hide_id]])</description></item><item><title>now</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/now/</guid><description>Return the time in seconds since the epoch as a floating point number.
If you require the same time multiple times within a query, then call now() only once and save it to a variable, for example now = now();
This function does not generate a change.
Function now()
Arguments None
Return value Current timestamp.
Example This code shows the current timestamp:
// current timestamp now(); Example return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>raise</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/raise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/raise/</guid><description>Raises an error.
This function does not generate a change.
Function raise([error])
Arguments Argument Type Description value error/str (optional) The error to raise. Return value None
Example Some examples on how raise() can be used:
raise (); // raise a default error 'This code is not reached'; raise ('no licenses left'); // raise with a custom message 'This code is not reached'; raise (value_err()); // raise a value error 'This code is not reached';</description></item><item><title>rand</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/rand/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/rand/</guid><description>Returns pseudo-random number between 0.0 and 1.0.
Do not use rand() when the purpose is security related since the linear congruential algorithms used by this function are too easy to break.
This function does not generate a change.
Function rand()
Arguments None
Return value A pseudo-random float number between 0.0 and 1.0.
Example Some examples on how raise() can be used:
// Return a pseudo-random number between 0.</description></item><item><title>randint</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/randint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/randint/</guid><description>Returns pseudo-random integer number between a given range.
The first argument specifies the start of the range and must have a value less than the second argument when specifies the end of the range. The start is inclusive and the end is exclusive, for example: randint(0, 2) will return either 0 or 1.
Do not use randint() when the purpose is security related since the linear congruential algorithms used by this function are too easy to break.</description></item><item><title>randstr</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/randstr/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/randstr/</guid><description>Returns a string with random characters.
The default characters to generate a string are URL-safe and contain the characters 0-9, A-Z, a-z, - and _.
Instead of the default character set, it is possible to use your own set. This custom set may contain duplicated characters which increase the chance for certain characters to occur in the final string. For example, a random string based on the character set AAB will most likely contain more A&amp;rsquo;s than B&amp;rsquo;s.</description></item><item><title>range</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/range/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/range/</guid><description>This function returns a list of numbers, starting from 0 (by default), increments by 1 (by default), and ends at a specified number.
Function range() may only be used for relatively small lists. An operation_err() (maximum range length exceeded) will be raised when trying to create a list with more than 9999 numbers.
Function range(start, stop, step)
Arguments Argument Type Description start int (optional) An integer number specifying at which position to start.</description></item><item><title>refs</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/refs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/refs/</guid><description>Returns the reference count of a value.
Generally, the count returned is one higher than you might expect, because it includes the (temporary) reference.
Different nodes might return different reference values since the reference counter can be higher or lower depending on how the value is stored and used.
This function does not generate a change.
Function refs(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to return the reference count for.</description></item><item><title>regex</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/regex/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/regex/</guid><description>Create a new regular expression.
This function can be used to create a regular expression from a given pattern with optional flags.
This function does not generate a change.
Function regex(pattern, [flags])
Arguments Argument Type Description pattern str (required) The pattern to use as a regular expression. flags str (optional) Optional flags, see the regex for more information. Return value A new regular expression.</description></item><item><title>rename_enum</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/rename_enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/rename_enum/</guid><description>Rename an enum type.
This function generates a change.
Function rename_enum(current_name, new_name)
Arguments Argument Type Description current_name str (required) Current enum type name. new_name str (required) New name for the enum type. Return value Returns nil when successful.</description></item><item><title>rename_type</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/rename_type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/rename_type/</guid><description>Rename a type.
This function generates a change.
Function rename_type(current_name, new_name)
Arguments Argument Type Description current_name str (required) Current type name. new_name str (required) New name for the type. Return value Returns nil when successful.</description></item><item><title>room</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/room/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/room/</guid><description>Returns a room from a specified value, that may be dynamic. If no value is given, a new room is returned.
This function does not generate a change.
Function room([id])
Arguments Argument Type Description id int (optional) The Id for the room to return. Return value Returns a room. A lookup_err() is returned in case a room Id is given which is not found inside the collection.</description></item><item><title>set</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/set/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/set/</guid><description>Returns a new empty set. If an array is given, then all items in the given array must be of type thing and a new set is returned based on the given things. Instead of an array, it is also possible to provide one thing or multiple comma-separated things.
This function does not generate a change.
Function set(array_or_things)
Arguments Argument Type Description array_or_things array/set/things (optional) Optional array or things to initialize the set.</description></item><item><title>set_enum</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/set_enum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/set_enum/</guid><description>Creates a new enumerator type.
This function generates a change.
Function set_enum(enum, members)
Arguments Argument Type Description enum str The name of the enumerator type to create. members thing Thing containing all the members to be set. Return value The value nil.
Example This code shows how to use set_enum():
set_enum('Status', { OK: 0, NOK: -1 }); Return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>set_type</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/set_type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/set_type/</guid><description>Defines the properties of a Type. Function set_type works only on a new Type. Use mod_type() if you want to change an existing Type, see mod_type.
This function generates a change.
Function set_type(type, value, [wrap_only, [hide_id]])
Arguments Argument Type Description type str The name of the Type where the properties have to be set. value thing Thing containing all the properties to be set.</description></item><item><title>str</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/str/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/str/</guid><description>Convert a value to a string. If no value is given, an empty string &amp;quot;&amp;quot; is returned.
When bytes are converted to str then the data will be checked if it contains valid UTF-8 characters. If this is not the case, a value_err() will be raised.
This function does not generate a change.
Function str(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (optional) The value to create a string from.</description></item><item><title>task</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/task/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/task/</guid><description>Create a new task or get an existing task by Id.
Using an Id as a single argument, this function can be used to return an existing task. With tasks() you can get a list with all available tasks.
This function generates a change.
Function task(Id) (get a task by Id) task(start, code, [args]) (create a new task)
Arguments Argument Type Description Id int (required) The Id of the task to return.</description></item><item><title>tasks</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/tasks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/tasks/</guid><description>Return a list with all the tasks in the current scope.
This function does not generate a change.
Function tasks()
Arguments None
Return value A list with all the tasks in the current scope.
Example Example tasks():
tasks(); Example return value in JSON format
[ &amp;#34;&amp;lt;task:9 owner:admin run_at:nil status:err&amp;gt;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;lt;task:10 owner:admin run_at:2021-11-03T12:43:57Z status:nil&amp;gt;&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;&amp;lt;task:26 owner:admin run_at:2021-11-03T20:00:00Z status:nil&amp;gt;&amp;#34; ] Example how to use tasks() to get all task Ids:</description></item><item><title>thing</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/thing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/thing/</guid><description>Returns a thing from a specified value, that may be dynamic. If no value is given, a new thing is returned.
This function does not generate a change.
Function thing([id])
Arguments Argument Type Description id int (optional) The Id for the thing to return. Return value Returns a thing. A lookup_err() is returned in case an Id is given which is not found inside the collection.</description></item><item><title>time_zones_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/time_zones_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/time_zones_info/</guid><description>Returns all available time zones in ThingsDB.
The function is_time_zone(..) can be used to check if a given str contains a time zone known by ThingsDB.
This function does not generate a change.
Function time_zones_info()
Arguments None
Return value Returns a list with all available time zones in ThingsDB.
Available Time Zones Africa/Abidjan Africa/Accra Africa/Addis_Ababa Africa/Algiers Africa/Asmara Africa/Bamako Africa/Bangui Africa/Banjul Africa/Bissau Africa/Blantyre Africa/Brazzaville Africa/Bujumbura Africa/Cairo Africa/Casablanca Africa/Ceuta Africa/Conakry Africa/Dakar Africa/Dar_es_Salaam Africa/Djibouti Africa/Douala Africa/El_Aaiun Africa/Freetown Africa/Gaborone Africa/Harare Africa/Johannesburg Africa/Juba Africa/Kampala Africa/Khartoum Africa/Kigali Africa/Kinshasa Africa/Lagos Africa/Libreville Africa/Lome Africa/Luanda Africa/Lubumbashi Africa/Lusaka Africa/Malabo Africa/Maputo Africa/Maseru Africa/Mbabane Africa/Mogadishu Africa/Monrovia Africa/Nairobi Africa/Ndjamena Africa/Niamey Africa/Nouakchott Africa/Ouagadougou Africa/Porto-Novo Africa/Sao_Tome Africa/Tripoli Africa/Tunis Africa/Windhoek America/Adak America/Anchorage America/Anguilla America/Antigua America/Araguaina America/Argentina/Buenos_Aires America/Argentina/Catamarca America/Argentina/Cordoba America/Argentina/Jujuy America/Argentina/La_Rioja America/Argentina/Mendoza America/Argentina/Rio_Gallegos America/Argentina/Salta America/Argentina/San_Juan America/Argentina/San_Luis America/Argentina/Tucuman America/Argentina/Ushuaia America/Aruba America/Asuncion America/Atikokan America/Bahia America/Bahia_Banderas America/Barbados America/Belem America/Belize America/Blanc-Sablon America/Boa_Vista America/Bogota America/Boise America/Cambridge_Bay America/Campo_Grande America/Cancun America/Caracas America/Cayenne America/Cayman America/Chicago America/Chihuahua America/Costa_Rica America/Creston America/Cuiaba America/Curacao America/Danmarkshavn America/Dawson America/Dawson_Creek America/Denver America/Detroit America/Dominica America/Edmonton America/Eirunepe America/El_Salvador America/Fort_Nelson America/Fortaleza America/Glace_Bay America/Goose_Bay America/Grand_Turk America/Grenada America/Guadeloupe America/Guatemala America/Guayaquil America/Guyana America/Halifax America/Havana America/Hermosillo America/Indiana/Indianapolis America/Indiana/Knox America/Indiana/Marengo America/Indiana/Petersburg America/Indiana/Tell_City America/Indiana/Vevay America/Indiana/Vincennes America/Indiana/Winamac America/Inuvik America/Iqaluit America/Jamaica America/Juneau America/Kentucky/Louisville America/Kentucky/Monticello America/Kralendijk America/La_Paz America/Lima America/Los_Angeles America/Lower_Princes America/Maceio America/Managua America/Manaus America/Marigot America/Martinique America/Matamoros America/Mazatlan America/Menominee America/Merida America/Metlakatla America/Mexico_City America/Miquelon America/Moncton America/Monterrey America/Montevideo America/Montserrat America/Nassau America/New_York America/Nipigon America/Nome America/Noronha America/North_Dakota/Beulah America/North_Dakota/Center America/North_Dakota/New_Salem America/Nuuk America/Ojinaga America/Panama America/Pangnirtung America/Paramaribo America/Phoenix America/Port-au-Prince America/Port_of_Spain America/Porto_Velho America/Puerto_Rico America/Punta_Arenas America/Rainy_River America/Rankin_Inlet America/Recife America/Regina America/Resolute America/Rio_Branco America/Santarem America/Santiago America/Santo_Domingo America/Sao_Paulo America/Scoresbysund America/Sitka America/St_Barthelemy America/St_Johns America/St_Kitts America/St_Lucia America/St_Thomas America/St_Vincent America/Swift_Current America/Tegucigalpa America/Thule America/Thunder_Bay America/Tijuana America/Toronto America/Tortola America/Vancouver America/Whitehorse America/Winnipeg America/Yakutat America/Yellowknife Antarctica/Casey Antarctica/Davis Antarctica/DumontDUrville Antarctica/Macquarie Antarctica/Mawson Antarctica/McMurdo Antarctica/Palmer Antarctica/Rothera Antarctica/Syowa Antarctica/Troll Antarctica/Vostok Arctic/Longyearbyen Asia/Aden Asia/Almaty Asia/Amman Asia/Anadyr Asia/Aqtau Asia/Aqtobe Asia/Ashgabat Asia/Atyrau Asia/Baghdad Asia/Bahrain Asia/Baku Asia/Bangkok Asia/Barnaul Asia/Beirut Asia/Bishkek Asia/Brunei Asia/Chita Asia/Choibalsan Asia/Colombo Asia/Damascus Asia/Dhaka Asia/Dili Asia/Dubai Asia/Dushanbe Asia/Famagusta Asia/Gaza Asia/Hebron Asia/Ho_Chi_Minh Asia/Hong_Kong Asia/Hovd Asia/Irkutsk Asia/Jakarta Asia/Jayapura Asia/Jerusalem Asia/Kabul Asia/Kamchatka Asia/Karachi Asia/Kathmandu Asia/Khandyga Asia/Kolkata Asia/Krasnoyarsk Asia/Kuala_Lumpur Asia/Kuching Asia/Kuwait Asia/Macau Asia/Magadan Asia/Makassar Asia/Manila Asia/Muscat Asia/Nicosia Asia/Novokuznetsk Asia/Novosibirsk Asia/Omsk Asia/Oral Asia/Phnom_Penh Asia/Pontianak Asia/Pyongyang Asia/Qatar Asia/Qostanay Asia/Qyzylorda Asia/Riyadh Asia/Sakhalin Asia/Samarkand Asia/Seoul Asia/Shanghai Asia/Singapore Asia/Srednekolymsk Asia/Taipei Asia/Tashkent Asia/Tbilisi Asia/Tehran Asia/Thimphu Asia/Tokyo Asia/Tomsk Asia/Ulaanbaatar Asia/Urumqi Asia/Ust-Nera Asia/Vientiane Asia/Vladivostok Asia/Yakutsk Asia/Yangon Asia/Yekaterinburg Asia/Yerevan Atlantic/Azores Atlantic/Bermuda Atlantic/Canary Atlantic/Cape_Verde Atlantic/Faroe Atlantic/Madeira Atlantic/Reykjavik Atlantic/South_Georgia Atlantic/St_Helena Atlantic/Stanley Australia/Adelaide Australia/Brisbane Australia/Broken_Hill Australia/Currie Australia/Darwin Australia/Eucla Australia/Hobart Australia/Lindeman Australia/Lord_Howe Australia/Melbourne Australia/Perth Australia/Sydney Canada/Atlantic Canada/Central Canada/Eastern Canada/Mountain Canada/Newfoundland Canada/Pacific Europe/Amsterdam Europe/Andorra Europe/Astrakhan Europe/Athens Europe/Belgrade Europe/Berlin Europe/Bratislava Europe/Brussels Europe/Bucharest Europe/Budapest Europe/Busingen Europe/Chisinau Europe/Copenhagen Europe/Dublin Europe/Gibraltar Europe/Guernsey Europe/Helsinki Europe/Isle_of_Man Europe/Istanbul Europe/Jersey Europe/Kaliningrad Europe/Kiev Europe/Kirov Europe/Lisbon Europe/Ljubljana Europe/London Europe/Luxembourg Europe/Madrid Europe/Malta Europe/Mariehamn Europe/Minsk Europe/Monaco Europe/Moscow Europe/Oslo Europe/Paris Europe/Podgorica Europe/Prague Europe/Riga Europe/Rome Europe/Samara Europe/San_Marino Europe/Sarajevo Europe/Saratov Europe/Simferopol Europe/Skopje Europe/Sofia Europe/Stockholm Europe/Tallinn Europe/Tirane Europe/Ulyanovsk Europe/Uzhgorod Europe/Vaduz Europe/Vatican Europe/Vienna Europe/Vilnius Europe/Volgograd Europe/Warsaw Europe/Zagreb Europe/Zaporozhye Europe/Zurich GMT Indian/Antananarivo Indian/Chagos Indian/Christmas Indian/Cocos Indian/Comoro Indian/Kerguelen Indian/Mahe Indian/Maldives Indian/Mauritius Indian/Mayotte Indian/Reunion Pacific/Apia Pacific/Auckland Pacific/Bougainville Pacific/Chatham Pacific/Chuuk Pacific/Easter Pacific/Efate Pacific/Enderbury Pacific/Fakaofo Pacific/Fiji Pacific/Funafuti Pacific/Galapagos Pacific/Gambier Pacific/Guadalcanal Pacific/Guam Pacific/Honolulu Pacific/Kiritimati Pacific/Kosrae Pacific/Kwajalein Pacific/Majuro Pacific/Marquesas Pacific/Midway Pacific/Nauru Pacific/Niue Pacific/Norfolk Pacific/Noumea Pacific/Pago_Pago Pacific/Palau Pacific/Pitcairn Pacific/Pohnpei Pacific/Port_Moresby Pacific/Rarotonga Pacific/Saipan Pacific/Tahiti Pacific/Tarawa Pacific/Tongatapu Pacific/Wake Pacific/Wallis US/Alaska US/Arizona US/Central US/Eastern US/Hawaii US/Mountain US/Pacific UTC</description></item><item><title>timeval</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/timeval/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/timeval/</guid><description>Returns a timeval depending on some optional values.
This function does not generate a change.
Function Interface Arguments Description timeval() None Return a timeval with the current date/tine. timeval(ts) int/float Return a timeval from a given UNIX time stamp. timeval(str, [fmt]) str Return a timeval from a given string. See initialize from string for a details. datetime(int, int, int, [int, [int, [int]]], [zone]) int, int,&amp;hellip; str Return a timeval using values for individual time units, with optional time zone.</description></item><item><title>try</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/try/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/try/</guid><description>Try a statement and if the statement fails with an error, then the error is returned. It is also possible to catch only specific errors.
It is not possible to catch internal errors. Such errors should never happen, unless something is really wrong with at least one node.
This function does not generate a change.
Function try(statement, [e0, e1, ..., eX])
Arguments Argument Type Description statement any (required) The statement to try.</description></item><item><title>type</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type/</guid><description>Returns the type name of a value.
This function does not generate a change.
Function type(value)
Arguments Argument Type Description value any (required) The value to return the type name for. Return value Type name of the given value.
Example Returns the type name of a given value:
[ type( nil ), type( 42 ), type( 3.14 ), ]; Example return value in JSON format</description></item><item><title>type_assert</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type_assert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type_assert/</guid><description>Raises a type_err() if the specified expression evaluates to false.
This function does not generate a change.
Function assert(expression, type(s) [, error_msg])
Arguments Argument Type Description expression any (required) The result of this expression will be type tested. type(s) str/list (required) Type name or list with type names to check. error_msg str (optional) Custom error message. Return value Returns nil if the type of the expression evaluates to true.</description></item><item><title>type_count</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type_count/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type_count/</guid><description>Returns the number of instances of a given Type within a collection.
This function does not generate a change.
Function type_count(type)
Arguments Argument Type Description type str The name of the Type for which the number of instances must be returned. Return value An int representing the number of occurrences.</description></item><item><title>type_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/type_info/</guid><description>Returns information about a given Type.
Value Description type_id Internal Type Id. created_at Time Stamp when the Type is created. modified_at Time Stamp when the Type is last modified or nil if never modified. name Type&amp;rsquo;s name. fields Array with arrays containing two strings, the property name and definition. methods Object with methods where the key is the method name and the value an object containing information about the closure.</description></item><item><title>types_info</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/types_info/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/types_info/</guid><description>Returns Type information about all the Types within a collection.
See the type_info() function documentation for an example of the exposed Type information.
This function does not generate a change.
Function types_info()
Arguments None
Return value List with Type mpdata about all Types in the collection.</description></item><item><title>wse</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/wse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v1/collection-api/wse/</guid><description>This function enforces ThingsDB to create a change.
When using a stored closure which requires a change it might not be possible for ThingsDB to detect the change requirement before evaluation the query. In this case it is required to use wse() to enforce a change.
Function wse() might both wrap a statement and be called without arguments.
This function generates a change.
Function wse([statement])
Arguments Argument Type Description statement any (optional) Statement or block to wrap.</description></item></channel></rss>