<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Node API on ThingsDB documentation</title>
    <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Node API on ThingsDB documentation</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>backup_info</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/backup_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/backup_info/</guid>
      <description>Returns information about a specific scheduled backup.
   Value Description     file_template Backup file template.   id Backup ID.   next_run Only available when the backup job is scheduled to run. Contains a string with date/time for the next planned schedule, or pending when the backup is scheduled to start.   repeat Only available when the backup will repeat. Contains an integer value representing the repeat time in seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>backups_info</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/backups_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/backups_info/</guid>
      <description>Returns backup schedule information for all backup schedules in the selected node scope.
See the backup_info() function documentation for an example of the exposed backup schedule information.
This function does not generate an event.
Function backups_info()
Arguments None
Return value List with backup schedule info for all backup schedules in the selected node scope.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>counters</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/counters/</guid>
      <description>Returns counters for the ThingsDB node in the selected scope. Counters start all at zero when ThingsDB is started, or when the counters are reset by using reset_counters()&amp;rsquo;.
Counters give information about things, queries and events. If you suspect failed queries, then counters might provide you with more information.
   Counter Description     average_event_duration The average event duration in seconds.   average_query_duration The average query duration in seconds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>del_backup</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/del_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/del_backup/</guid>
      <description>Delete a scheduled backup. If the schedule was pending, the backup job will be cancelled.
Files associated with the backup will not be removed. Only the schedule will be deleted.
 This function does not generate an event.
Function del_backup(ID);
Arguments    Argument Type Description     ID int Backup ID to delete.    Return value Returns nil.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>has_backup</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/has_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/has_backup/</guid>
      <description>Determines if a backup exists in ThingsDB.
This function does not generate an event.
Function has_backup(ID)
Arguments    Argument Type Description     ID int (required) Backup ID to check.    Return value Returns true a backup with a given ID exists and otherwise false.
Example  This code shows an example use case of has_backup():
 has_backup(123);   Return value in JSON format</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>new_backup</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/new_backup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/new_backup/</guid>
      <description>Schedule a new backup.
Backups are created using tar and gzip. Once a backup is made, the .tar.gz backup file can be used to recover ThingsDB, or can be used to load the ThingsDB into another node. The result value is a backup ID. This ID can be used by backup_info(..) for details about the backup schedule job, or can be used to delete the backup schedule.
See the example recovery section below on how to recover from a backup file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>node_info</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/node_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/node_info/</guid>
      <description>Returns information about the node in the selected scope. See scopes for more information on how to target a specific node scope.
   Value Description     archive_files Number of archive files. May decrease after a full store during away mode.   archived_in_memory Number of events which are archived in memory.   cached_names Number of names cached in memory.   client_port Listening for client TCP socket connections on this port.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>nodes_info</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/nodes_info/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/nodes_info/</guid>
      <description>Returns information about all ThingsDB nodes.
   Value Description     address IP address or hostname of the node.   committed_event_id Last known committed event ID on the node.   next_thing_id Next free thing ID on the node.   node_id ID which is assigned to the node.   port TCP port on which the node is listening for node connections.   status Current status of the node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reset_counters</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/reset_counters/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/reset_counters/</guid>
      <description> Resets the counters for the ThingsDB node you are connected too. Other nodes are not affected.
This function does not generate an event.
Function reset_counters();
Arguments None
Return value Returns nil.
Example  This code will reset the counters on a node:
 // resets counters on `localhost:9200` reset_counters();   Example return value in JSON format (the new collection id)
 null  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>set_log_level</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/set_log_level/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/set_log_level/</guid>
      <description>Change the log level for the node in the selected scope.
ThingsDB will then log all levels greater than or equal to the specified level. For example, a default log_level of warning will log warning, error and critical messages.
This function does not generate an event.
Log Levels    Name Int Description     DEBUG 0 Display debug messages (can result in large amount of logging).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>shutdown</title>
      <link>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://docs.thingsdb.net/v0/node-api/shutdown/</guid>
      <description>Shutdown the node in the selected scope. This is a clean shutdown, allowing all other nodes (and clients) to disconnect.
At least MODIFY privileges on the @node scope are required to shutdown a node.
 This function does not generate an event.
Function shutdown();
Arguments None.
Return value Returns nil.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>