<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mod_type on ThingsDB documentation</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/</link><description>Recent content in mod_type on ThingsDB documentation</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>add</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/add/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/add/</guid><description>Adds a property or method to an existing Type.
Since version v0.9.2 an initial value is no longer required when having active instances of the given Type. If the initial value is omitted, then a single default value according the Type definition will be created and applied to all instances. See section &amp;ldquo;init using callback&amp;rdquo; for information on how to create a new initial value for each instance.
Action mod_type(type, 'add', name, definition/closure, [init])</description></item><item><title>all</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/all/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/all/</guid><description>Run a given callback on all the instances of a given Type.
Use type_all(..) if you just need a set with all instances.
This function should be used for migration purposes and not for common queries as the function is rather slow. When calling this action, ThingsDB requires to loop over all the things in the collection, including the things which are marked for garbage collection.
Action mod_type(type, 'all', callback)</description></item><item><title>del</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/del/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/del/</guid><description>Deletes a property or method from an existing Type.
A property will be removed from all the active instances of that Type.
Action mod_type(type, 'del', name)
Arguments Argument Type Description type str Name of the Type where the property has to be removed from. 'del' str Passing this argument will result in a delete action. name str Name of the property or method that has to be removed.</description></item><item><title>hid</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/hid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/hid/</guid><description>Enable or disable hide-id for an existing Type.
When hide-id is enabled, this type will not return the Id property to the client unless deep is equal to zero (0) in which case only the Id is returned. This last behavior is different from the NO_IDS flag which can be used for example with the return statement. (The NO_IDS flag would return empty things when deep is 0)
Action mod_type(type, 'hid', mode)</description></item><item><title>idx</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/idx/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/idx/</guid><description>Enable or disable auto-index for an existing Type.
When auto-index is enabled, this type will use an internal index for type_all(..) function calls, making them significatly faster, especially in collections with many things.
Action mod_type(type, 'idx', mode)
Arguments Argument Type Description type str Name of the Type where to set auto-index on or off. 'idx' str Passing this argument will result in a *set-auto-index action.</description></item><item><title>mod</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/mod/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/mod/</guid><description>Modifies the type definition of a property or the closure of a method from an existing Type. It is not possible to convert a property to a method or the other way around.
Without an additional callback it is possible to modify to a less &amp;lsquo;strict&amp;rsquo; definition. So for example, age: 'int' can become age: 'int?', but not the other way around. Since version v0.9.3 it is possible to migrate to a more strict or completely different definition by using an additional callback closure for generating new values.</description></item><item><title>rel</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/rel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/rel/</guid><description>Add or delete a relation between properties of the same or different types.
Relations can only be created between nillable type definitions and/or restricted sets. This results in the following combinations:
Combination Description Type? &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; Type? One to one relation. Type? &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; {Type} One to many relation. {Type} &amp;lt;-&amp;gt; {Type} Many to many relation. All missing relations on existing instances will be automatically created by ThingsDB once you add a new relation.</description></item><item><title>ren</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/ren/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/ren/</guid><description>Rename a property or method from an existing Type.
Action mod_type(type, 'ren', name, to)
Arguments Argument Type Description type str Name of the Type where the property or method has to be modified from. 'ren' str Passing this argument will result in a modify action. name str Name of the property or method that has to be modified. to str New name for the property or method that has to be modified.</description></item><item><title>wpo</title><link>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/wpo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://docs.thingsdb.io/v1/collection-api/mod_type/wpo/</guid><description>Enable or disable wrap-only mode for an existing Type.
When wrap-only mode is enabled, no instances of the type can be created and the type can not be used by other type unless that type is also in wrap-only mode. The only purpose of a type in wrap-only mode is to wrap things with but this gives you the assurance that no data is created using this type.
Enable wrap-only mode To enable wrap-only mode, make sure no instances of this type exist, and also be sure that no other type without wrap-only mode is dependent on the type you want to change.</description></item></channel></rss>